# ROHIT KHANDELWAL

LEAD ESG TRAINER -



Train The Trainer and GRI Certified adaptable product and process trainer with extensive experience in providing exemplary trainings for ESG, Sustainability, Investment Banking Operations and Capital Markets. Meeting Learning & Development demands and deadlines through a diligent work-ethic and dedication to knowledge enhancement.

### CONTACT

PHONE

+91-9561948784



E - MAIL

khandelwal.rohit8@gmail.com



in LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/rohitkhandelwal-8a919922

ADDRESS

Hyderabad, Telangana State

### **EDUCATION**

2008-2010

# **MASTERS OF BUSINESS** ADMINISTRATION

Institute of Chartered Financial Analysts of India.

Mumbai

**GRI Reporting Certified BCG - ESG Job Simulation** 

2005-2008 **BACHELOR OF COMMERCE** 

Symbiosis International Pune, Maharashtra

## WORK EXPERIENCE —

**September 2020-Present** 

#### **Lead ESG Trainer- Product and Client Service**

INTERCONTINENTAL EXCHANGE, INC. (ICE), Hyd

Acquired proficiency in ESG training aspects, authored data policies for clients and oversaw end to end product and process training.

- Product & Process Training Meticulous training delivery on core ESG concepts across 3 locations to New Hires, Senior and Mid Management employees. Conducted 150+ ESG training sessions for external and internal clients/stakeholders.
- Bite Size Learning Formulated Bite Size Learning and E- Learning modules for Stakeholders on complex ESG concepts like Carbon Price, EU - Taxonomy and GHG Targets.
- Climate Transition Finance Project Analyzation and Standardization of the data set which is specific to GHG Emissions and External Assurance. Designed validation rules for cross data check and correctness.
- Training Need Analysis Concluded and Capitalized on Time Gap Analysis of 4000 North America Region Profiles and saved 2.5 FTE for production team.
- **Document Repository Crafted all process documents and reference** manuals. Initiated standardization of policy roll outs & validation rules. Maintained version control of all process documents.

#### ADDITIONAL WORK TASK -

- Supervised trainee performance and directed real time feedback.
- Organize data records, audit trails and records for Internal Audit.
- Create and maintain client records and process document repository
- Assist Business Analyst Team in product Testing/reviews.

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

- Foreign Exchange Risk Management in Banks
- Monetary and Fiscal Policy of Indian Economy (MBA Project)
- Demand and Supply Analysis of Indian Railways
- Monitoring Bond Market

  Performance (Summer Internship)

# **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Environmental, Social, and Governance (ESG) Reporting
- Capital Markets and Investments
- Learning and Development (L&D)
- Design Thinking and Innovation
- Change Management
- Mentorship

# PEOPLE SKILLS

- **Communication**
- Adaptability
- **Empathy**
- Collaboration
- **▶** Problem-Solving
- > Time Management
- Leadership
- **▶** Flexibility

#### LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Marathi

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Wipro LTD (August 2017 - August 2020) :

### **Senior Product Trainer -**

End to End training deliveries on all Capital Market products and process for 5 Investment Banks across 5 Locations. Gained proficiency on creating and repository of process documents. Learned and conceptualized BYTE SIZE, GAMIFICATION and TNA/TNI concepts.

Deutsche Bank India Pvt Ltd ( August 2013 - August 2017) : Senior Analyst -

Accurate and timely booking of trades **(99% accuracy)** for 7 stock exchanges across Asia Pacific region. Impeccably work on trade funding, compliance & regulatory reporting. Training new hires and Seniors.

Morgan Stanley Advantage Services (March 2011 - April 2013) : Senior Analyst -

Developed a strong capability to understand equity and derivatives Trade booking, Trade Validation and Reconciliation for Europe & North America region. Gained thorough knowledge of Hedge Funds and Trade Life Cycle.

Bharati AXA Investment Managers Pvt Ltd (March 2010 - March 2011)
Analyst -

Tracking and maintaining performance of Debt Market Mutual Funds. Formulate expense ratio , M2M profile and loss statements. Attend client calls and meetings.

### CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

- GRI Reporting Certified: Achieved certification in GRI reporting, demonstrating expertise in sustainability reporting standards.
- "Train the Trainer" Certified: Completed certification in training methodology, showcasing proficiency in designing and delivering effective training programs.
- TCFD Certification: Certified in the Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures (TCFD), indicating competence in climate-related financial risk assessment and reporting.
- **Design Thinking:** Completed a course on understanding the design thinking process, enhancing problem-solving and innovation skills.
- 34 Things to Know About Carbon and Climate Change: Gained comprehensive insights into the complexities of carbon emissions and climate change.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Promotion to Lead Trainer: Achieved promotion to Lead Trainer in 2023, reflecting recognition of leadership and expertise in Business delivery.
- Trainer of the Quarter Award: Received the "Trainer of the Quarter" award for Q3 2018, highlighting exceptional performance and impact in training initiatives.
- Vast Training Experience: Delivered classroom training for over 4000 trainees, demonstrating a proven track record of effectively transferring knowledge and skills.
- Contribution to Award-Winning Team: Member of the "Best Trade Support Group-2011-CEO Choice", showcasing collaborative success and contribution to organizational excellence.

## DECLARATION